<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-19T14:53:03+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Emma Movsesyan</title><subtitle>This my online mindbook, where I am saring the things I learn.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Nihilism, Dostoevskiy, “The Idiot”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/07/10/nihilism-dostoevskiy-the-idiot.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nihilism, Dostoevskiy, &quot;The Idiot&quot;" /><published>2018-07-10T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2018-07-10T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/07/10/nihilism-dostoevskiy-the-idiot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/07/10/nihilism-dostoevskiy-the-idiot.html">&lt;style&gt;
    body {
        margin: auto;
    	width: 50%;
    	padding-top:5%;
    }		
	a {
		text-decoration: none;
		color:#C0D7EF;
	}
	h3 {
		color:grey;
	}
	h1 {
		color:#C0D7EF;
	}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nihilism&quot;&gt;Nihilism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before going into the analyses of the book, I would like to share the new perspective I have gained about the world’s philosophy, when I was introduced to the word “nihilism”.  In Wikipedia its stated that “Nihilism is the philosophical viewpoint that suggests the denial or lack of belief towards the reputedly meaningful aspects of life. Most commonly, nihilism is presented in the form of existential nihilism, which argues that life is without objective meaning, purpose, or intrinsic value.” While, this explanation made the boarder between nihilsm and existentialism very vogue. Due to &lt;a href=&quot;https://danielmiessler.com/blog/difference-existentialism-nihilism-absurdism/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; article I was able to differentiate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Existentialism&lt;/strong&gt; - is the belief that through a combination of awareness, free will, and personal responsibility, one can construct their own meaning within a world that intrinsically has none of its own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nihilism&lt;/strong&gt;  - is the belief that not only is there no intrinsic meaning in the universe, but that it’s pointless to try to construct our own as a substitute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to make a list of famous Nihilists still most of the ones I wanted to mention were already listed as existentialists.
(Must explore the difference further to understand Why)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Absurdism&lt;/strong&gt; -  is the belief that a search for meaning is inherently in conflict with the actual lack of meaning, but that one should both accept this and simultaneously rebel against it by embracing what life has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Superior Existentialists(Dane Søren Kierkegaard (1813–1855) was a theologian, German Friedrich Nietzsche (1844–1900) an anti-establishment wandering academic, Czech Franz Kafka (1883–1924) a short story writer and factory manager, and Russian Fyodor Dostoyevsky (1821–1881) a novelist, Albert Camus, Simone de Beauvoir, Jean-Paul Sartre etc. ) *
I wanted to make a list of famous nihilists and absurdists still most of the ones I wanted to mention were already listed as existentialists.(Must explore the difference further to understand Why)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;interesting-facts-about-fyodor-dostoevsky&quot;&gt;Interesting Facts about Fyodor Dostoevsky&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dostoevsky’s literary works explore human psychology in the troubled political, social, and spiritual atmospheres of 19th-century Russia, and engage with a variety of realistic philosophical and religious themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;worked as an engineer and briefly enjoyed a lavish lifestyle&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;spent four years in a Siberian prison camp&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;began to travel around western Europe and developed a gambling addiction&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;kept Russian Orthodox beliefs&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MMmSdxZpseY&quot;&gt;Source1&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fyodor_Dostoevsky&quot;&gt;Source2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-idiot&quot;&gt;The Idiot&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first novel I have read from Dostoevskiy. I am amazed by the tone that he is using to describe P. Myshkin. I fell in love with that character within the first pages. The character encapsulating all the factors converging to the ideal one. His transparency, analytical thinking, humbleness, intelligence and the deepness could not help me not to fall in love with him.
(In the beginning I was really enjoying the “maybe”-s he was using very frequently in his sentences). I have finished the novel 30 minutes ago and I am sitting with a complete mess in my mind, having a lot of questions that I can not find the answers to.&lt;br /&gt;
Myshkin was the character I was searching in me for very long, and when it seemes to me that I have converged to the consciousness and self-purpose I have started reading this book. And the analogues that I was observing through inrospecting my ideal self and Myshkin’s character were mind blowing. Those made me to enjoy the novel more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is certainly one of the greatest novels I have read!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;favourite-parts-translated-from-the-russian-version-therefore-may-diverge-a-little-from-the-original&quot;&gt;Favourite parts (translated from the Russian version, therefore may diverge a little from the original)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There are those people very common in a socium that know everything, but their everything is truly constrained.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Education, intelligence and talent have made the Yepanchin’s girls quite unique. They read a lot, still were not yet interested in getting married.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My time is wholy mine.   (-Myshkin)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Himself, his tranquility and comfort he loved and appreciated more than anything else in the world, this was a sign of a higly intelligent(poryadochni) man.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He was talking with a naked straightforwardness.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I have been always happy there. I was going to bad happy and was waking up happier.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Firstly I was thinking that the cities I live in influence my happiness, then I have realized that even in the prison You can find a great life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sometimes I speak like I am teaching, but I know that I know the least possible about life.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You do not need to hide something from children, justifying that they are small or too small to understand. They have a lot to teach us.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is one thing I know for sure I do not like to spend time with the old, I am always failing with them. If I have a choice I always try to choose children. I am becomming extremely happy with them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I could never understand how and why people are becomming miserable?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The dumb with a heart and no brain, is equally unhappy as the dumb with the brain and no heart. (- Maman)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has reminded be about the misunderstanding I have about always referring to love as heart and not brain (Why?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This “Idiot” has this ability to grasp everything quickly and analytically.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Myshkin notices things that no one else could have noticed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is nothing more abusing(frustrating) to a person, than saying that he/she is not original, in other words is common.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The core is in a beauty, intelligence and determination …&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Russian parents are diverging from honesty and humblness. For ex. one of the parents was urging his child to overcome any obstacle in order to earn money.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He was one of those people: humble, honest, who transparently and consciously wants healthy staff. (very hard working and will always find a job)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The design of Your house vividely encapsulates the temperament of all of Your family members.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Even though he is a scientist, he is very humble and communicates with me as to an equall.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grateful and honest person is the same as the conscious person.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Before the Switzerland I was also unable to organize and intelligently state my ideas .&lt;/em&gt;
This reminds me once again how important the nurture is. How the new experience can exponentially impact the intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I want to live for a hapiness of all the others, for the exploration and for converging and raising the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Omg, Myshkin how SwissLike You still think!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You must be ashamed, those are Your purest emotions and You are hiding them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The only original and the dynamic people are capable of not becoming a Chinovnik. (p. 341)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Some stupidity must be common in all of those businessman.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Russian originals are: Lomonosov, Pushkin and Gogol. They are the only once who could have genuinely present their own unique ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You have taken a specific case and have generalized it, consequantly You are misleading!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The heaven on earth is not easily found, but Your honest mind still searches it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The loser is the one who is afraid and is escaping, the one who is afraid and is stayinng is not a loser.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He was always getting sad at the times when he was extremely happy.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The mankind is becomming very noisy and organized, there is a lack of the harmony in our souls.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Who is faulty about their unhappiness and poorness than themself?  (I have proved him that he is the reason of his poorness.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;All the people, except the Myshkin do not appreciate life as much as they should, they are cheaply consuming it, very lazily and unconsciously, therefore they do not deserve it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doing good , in any form, You are giving a part of Your identity and accepting the part from the other side. In this way You are becomming a whole, a little bit more attention and You are already gifted with a new knowledge (dimension). At some point You will start looking at this activity as on science, it will take and at the same time fill all of Your life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I do not want to go to their balls, I want to bring good.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I want to have at least one person with whom I can talk, as to myself.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When God wants to punish, he brightens our consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You cant love perfection, You can just watch it, right? Still, I am in love with You.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I think the common thing in those mediocre people is that they can not find what exactly they need to explore and what they would want to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I hate You as You are the encapsulation of the ordinary.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How childish we are , and that feels so good!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;People nowadays, are more nervous, devloped, sensitive and multidimensional. They are broader, and it may bother them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How I need to die? &lt;em&gt;Пройдите мимо нас и простите нам наше счастьe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;His charisma of flowless manners, simplicity and pure heart was near magical.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Atheism is proposing null, while Catholism is worse as it goes beyond that, it’s proposing the opposite of Christ the Anti Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In order to reach perfection, firstly You need to misunderstand a lot of things&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I cant understand how You can pass a tree and not be excited that You have passed it? Talk to a person and not be excited that You love him! Look(observe) the child, the sunrise, the growth of the green, observe the eyes that are looking at You and that love You.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Not being surprised is a sign of a great mind, while I think it could have applied to dumbs also.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There are cases that You are allowed to burn ships , leave home. Life is not just about breakfasts, lunches and princes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What You know about my current being, to judge me?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I was loving her through all the factors! 
&lt;em&gt;“Love has factors” approved :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What has started with a lie, must end with a lie,  that’s a law of nature.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I love both of them!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Free will and the money makes us different from other animals.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He considered his wedding a formality, he was poorly appreciating his own destiny.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>M4ML</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Books that have influenced my ideologies.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/29/my-book-list.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Books that have influenced my ideologies." /><published>2018-04-29T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2018-04-29T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/29/my-book-list</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/29/my-book-list.html">&lt;style&gt;
    body {
        margin: auto;
    	width: 50%;
    	padding-top:5%;
    }		
	a {
		text-decoration: none;
		color:#C0D7EF;
		}
	b, h3 {
		color:grey;
		}
	h1 {
		color:#C0D7EF;
	}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-list-of-books-that-worth-to-be-reread&quot;&gt;My list of books that worth to be reread&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In this article I will constantly share the books that I have enjoyed the most. Those were mostly the books that helped me to converge more to the answers that I have about this universe. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_to_Create_a_Mind&quot;&gt;“How to create a mind”&lt;/a&gt; written by Computer Scientist Ray Kurzweil &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This book has helped me to be interested more in human decision making and learning. I have been contemplating on those questions through making parallels between human brain and AI models. As my interest grew after every single page and theory raised by the professor I have finally decided to pursue a Cognitive Neuroscience Degree in Germany in the near future.&lt;br /&gt;
I recommend this book to every single person who doubts in the ability of human brain and the power of AI. This book gave me a big new breath and a very new dimension to explore the origins of life. The biggest question I am left with after reading the book is, to explore the difference between AI (conscious machines) and conscious homo sapiens.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Critics apply their linear intuition to information phenomena that are fundamentally exponential&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Indeed we resolve ambiguities in much the same way that Watson does- by considering the likelihood of different interpretations of a phrase.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;We are looking for biologically inspired methods that can accelerate work in AI, much of which has progressed without significant insight as to how the brain performs similar functions. I know that our work was greatly accelerated when we gained insights as to how the brain prepares and transforms auditory information.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;It is interesting to note that the methods deployed in AI have evolved to be mathematically very similar to the mechanisms in the neocortex.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Each neocortical pattern recognizer-indeed, each neuron and each neuronal component- is following an algorithm.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Waking up the universe, and then intelligently deciding its fate by infusing (integrating) it with our human intelligence
in its nonbiological form, is our destiny.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;i&gt;― Ray Kurzweil&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Art_of_Loving&quot;&gt; “The Art of Loving”&lt;/a&gt; written by Psychologist Erich Fromm&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I have read this book, after experiencing love. I have been experiencing something unsual and very tense, and I could not define it , as I have never experienced it before. Erich Fromm helped me to define my experience, and understand the deep and diverse roots of love.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &quot;Modern man thinks he loses something - time - when he does not do things quickly. Yet he does not know what to do with the time he gains, except kill it.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&quot;If one is not productive in other spheres, one is not productive in the love either.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt; &quot;If you love yourself, you love everybody else as you do yourself. As long as you love another person less than you love yourself, you will not really succeed in loving yourself, but if you love all alike, including yourself, you will love them as one person. Thus he is a great and righteous person who, loving himself, loves all others equally.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;i&gt;― Erich Fromm&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Stranger_(novel)&quot;&gt; “The Outsider” &lt;/a&gt;written by Philosopher Albert Camus&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&quot;I summarized The Stranger a long time ago, with a remark I admit was highly paradoxical: 'In our society any man who does not weep at his mother's funeral runs the risk of being sentenced to death.' I only meant that the hero of my book is condemned because he does not play the game.&quot;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;i&gt;― Albert Camus&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So, the reason I have included this book in the list, is that I always wondered why people could have been judged for not having or showing their feelings and emotions, but not for faking those. For me, the stranger's pure and transparent analyses of his actions help me in some sense figure out and question certain behaviours of mine.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>M4ML</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/markez.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Colombia, Gabriel García Márquez, “100 years of solitude”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/18/gabriel-garcia-marquez.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Colombia, Gabriel García Márquez, &quot;100 years of solitude&quot;" /><published>2018-04-18T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2018-04-18T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/18/gabriel-garcia-marquez</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/18/gabriel-garcia-marquez.html">&lt;style&gt;
    body {
        margin: auto;
    	width: 50%;
    	padding-top:5%;
    }		
	a {
		text-decoration: none;
		color:#C0D7EF;
	}
	h3 {
		color:grey;
	}
	h1 {
		color:#C0D7EF;
	}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;takeaways-from-one-hundred-years-of-solitude&quot;&gt;TakeAways from “One Hundred Years of Solitude”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gabriel  García Márquez  was a Colombian novelist. Before starting the analyses of the novel I always like to explore the territory where the writer was living. So, let us first of all try to explore Colombia.
I would like to figure out things that Colombia is known for first of all. I have used this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/What-is-Colombia-known-for&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; for reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; Negative things Colombia is known for:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pablo Escobar and all drug cartels in the 80s and early 90s.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;#1 producer of cocaine in the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Positive things Colombia is known for:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coffee. Colombian coffee is know all over the world for its softness .&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Emeralds. Best emeralds in the world.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pacemaker first functional one was developed by a Colombian, Jorge Reynolds.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gabriel García Márquez&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a great friend from Colombia, who was my roomate in the CIEE conference in a Washington D.C. Daniella Díaz! 
A very bright person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, as we know a little bit about the Colombia,  we are ready to narrow down and explore the biography of Markez.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He pursued a self-directed education that resulted in his leaving law school for a career in journalism. I guess this is one of the reasons he has grown up without any mind boarders and has created great novels for diverse auditory.
He was popular in style &lt;b&gt;magical realism&lt;/b&gt; , the style where the magical elements are integrated into the ordianry routine. This is another factor that makes his novels so grabbing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;García Márquez received the Nobel Prize in Literature  “for his novels and short stories, in which the fantastic and the realistic are combined in a richly composed world of imagination, reflecting a continent’s life and conflicts. Upon García Márquez’s death in April 2014, Juan Manuel Santos, the President of Colombia, called him “the greatest Colombian who ever lived. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gabriel_Garc%C3%ADa_M%C3%A1rquez#Nobel_Prize&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s summarize some takaways from the novel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed reading the analyses of Mr. Kiely who is a professor of English at Harvard.  You can find the article &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.nytimes.com/www.nytimes.com/books/97/06/15/reviews/marque-solitude.html?_r=1&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The novel is written in the language of a poet who knows the earth and does not fear it as the enemy of the dreamer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would share here the favorite parts from the previous review that in my perspective could not be depicted and appreciated more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is a history, not of governments or of formal institutions of the sort which keeps public records, but of a people who, like the earliest descendants of Abraham, are best understood in terms of their relationship to a single family. In a sense, José and Ursula are the only two characters in the story, and all their children, grandchildren and great-grandchildren are variations on their strengths and weaknesses. José, forever fascinated by the unknown, takes up project after project, invention after invention, in order among other things, to make gold, discover the ocean and photograph God. He eventually goes mad, smashes things, refuses to speak except in Latin and is tied to a giant chestnut tree in the middle of the family garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The novel excited me the most as, it gave me an opportunity to follow the rise, development, and the end of the whole Buendias (7 generations) in the small city of Macondo, that they have established. In the development process we are introduced to the way the Buendias love, explore the world, are fighting for their liberal believes. The novel becomes more grabbing when those magical elements are added to the realism. One of the points I think that can be inferred is that the evolution of generations is in some sense looped and is repeated with some relatively small additions. 
But I think that this inference will be true untill the point where the AI will transcend human intelligence, and after this I think that this loop will be broken. But what will follow after this broken loop, is a deep question that I think contemporary writers of magical realism will try to uleash…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources I have visited to see the percpectives of different people on the novel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0tK2xtK2OAk&quot;&gt;source 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shmoop.com/one-hundred-years-solitude/setting.html&quot;&gt;source 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.nytimes.com/www.nytimes.com/books/97/06/15/reviews/marque-solitude.html?_r=1&quot;&gt;source 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interesting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The sad Armenian (cigan) was putting a spell for making a man invisible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The novel was astonishing with it’s big sentences(2-3 pages)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important takeaway for me is, that we can always escape the antagonism and prejudice of the reality in doing things we love or exploring the universe through adding more dimensions in our minds. While, when is it worth doing? Is it good to always escape it and create our new idealistic reality? Who knows :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Favourite parts (translated from the Russian version, therefore may diverge a little from the original)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aureliano Buendia was not interested in trade, the work was helpin g him to fully concentrate, which helped him to find the pure harmony in himself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The secret to healthy aging is the calm acceptance of lonliness.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ursula was assured that thie time is built in circle, so everything is repeating.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The border of realliity was so blured that no one could have see it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The more Remedios the Beauty was realising herself from fashion, searching for comfort,  her beauty was becomming     more intriguing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Remedios the Beauty has tolled that will never marry a guy, who is capable of losing an hour of his life, while following a women taking a shower, risking with his lunch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The love was enough for Remedios the Beauty, but none of the man was converging to the true definition of it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ursula has noticed, that all of the family members are following exactly the same route daily, but even they were not noticing it. (We are definitely AI machines :) )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He will learn to think about her in a tranquilized manner, without awakening his feelings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meme was paying for her freedom with doing things that were not totally making her happy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time is moving in circle. (I am sure that this circle will be traced, at the point of singularity).
-Nothing interested him, maybe because he did not have any long term memories to relate with the things occuring around.
( interest~LTM)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In his alive and blue eyes the kindness was shining, a shine characterizing a man who have read all the books of the universe.
(kindness~books read (mind dimensions))&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Aurelianos purpose of reading books, was not in adding knowledge (mind dimensions), he was just searching the approval of the theories he was already aware about.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The time is enough for everything.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The appocalypse will be when people will travel in a first class, while books will be delievered seperately on trading vagons.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The lovers have lost the sense of reality, the understanding of time and have escaped their routine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>M4ML</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/markez.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Exploring 100 great authors!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/17/yes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exploring  100 great authors!" /><published>2018-04-17T22:44:00+04:00</published><updated>2018-04-17T22:44:00+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/17/yes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/17/yes.html">&lt;style&gt;
		a {
			 text-decoration: none;
			 color:#C0D7EF;
		}
		b, h3 {
			color:grey;
		}
		h1 {
		color:#C0D7EF;
		}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;takeaways-from-one-hundred-years-of-solitude&quot;&gt;TakeAways from “One Hundred Years of Solitude”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shaping my ideologies through great books!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have never been of those kids who were obsessed with books. But I was always inspired by people who read books and by people whose hobby was reading. One of my favorite quotes is “Fake it till You make it” , it is inspired by the disciplines of Sigmund Freud and Alfred Adler, who  developed a therapeutic technique that they called “acting as if”.&lt;br /&gt;
So, after I got accepted to the university I had a very clear goal that I must start reading and make it my hobby. So, already couple of years have past, I understood that there is no other activity that can add more dimensions to my brain than reading and exploring the great authors.&lt;br /&gt;
I was 16 when I have chosen by myself the first book in the library that has opened the doors to the great multidimensional world of books. This was a book shaping my introductory view on the discipline of philosophy. The book was “Sophie’s World” novel by Norwegian writer Jostein Gaarder. I would suggest it to every single person who wants to explore and start questioning this great universe through philosophy.&lt;br /&gt;
I am 21 years old now, I have read books from very diverse disciplines and authors. Today is the day I have decided to start accomplishing one of the goals of my bucket list. The goal is to read at least one novel from 100 greatest writers of the world. This is important for me as in this century of data it’s easy to find the best authors rated on very different factors and start to explore their life perspectives. I am taking as a reference the ranked list &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ranker.com/list/best-writers-of-all-time/ranker-books?ref=collections&amp;amp;l=684620&amp;amp;collectionId=1563&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. While I am not going to follow the presented sequence. The way I will choose the author from the list will depend on varios subjective  factors. 
I am starting with Gabriel García Márquez - “One Hundred Years of Solitude”. I will share my own analyses of the novel in the future post, which can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://m4ml.github.io/blog/2018/04/18/gabriel-garcia-marquez.html&quot;&gt;here &lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
I am also going to share my subjective list of great books that have shaped me and my beliefs &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;my book list &lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>M4ML</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/markdown.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">will be available soon</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/2018/04/17/indigo-jekyll-theme.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="will be available soon" /><published>2018-04-17T22:10:00+04:00</published><updated>2018-04-17T22:10:00+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/2018/04/17/indigo-jekyll-theme</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/2018/04/17/indigo-jekyll-theme.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/sergiokopplin/indigo/gh-pages/assets/screen-shot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example of project - Indigo Minimalist Jekyll Template - &lt;a href=&quot;http://sergiokopplin.github.io/indigo/&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;. This is a simple and minimalist template for Jekyll for those who likes to eat noodles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What has inside?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gulp&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BrowserSync&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stylus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SVG&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No JS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/insights/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fsergiokopplin.github.io%2Findigo%2F&quot;&gt;98/100&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sergiokopplin.github.io/indigo/&quot;&gt;Check it out&lt;/a&gt; here.
If you need some help, just &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/sergiokopplin/indigo/issues&quot;&gt;tell me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>johndoe</name></author><category term="project" /><category term="jekyll" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://koppl.in/indigo/assets/images/jekyll-logo-light-solid.png" /></entry></feed>